Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Capital Cities [includes color photographs], undated; 8 (Box 1539)
    - [Francis Joseph Spellman, Cardinal Archbishop of New York and Lowell Thomas], 18
    - [Francis Joseph Spellman, Cardinal Archbishop of New York and Lowell Thomas], 19
    - L.T. with Mgr. [Monseigneur ]John McMahon, Radio-TV director of Catholic Diocese of Western New York Robert J. Koch, Commercial Photographer, 193 E. Morris Ave., Buffalo 14, N.Y, 20
    - Verso: L.T. with Mgr. [Monseigneur ]John McMahon, Radio-TV director of Catholic Diocese of Western New York Robert J. Koch, Commercial Photographer, 193 E. Morris Ave., Buffalo 14, N.Y, 20-verso
    - Mr. Maurice Connell, TREASURER, Better Business Bureau, Mr. Verden Draper, PRESIDENT-ELECT, B.B.B. (General Partner, Price-Waterhouse, Buffalo), Mr. Edward Butler, PRESIDENT (1967), B.B.B. (President, McDougall-Butler Paint Co.), L.T., Mr. Abner Homburger, CHAIRMAN, Public Relations Committee, B.B.Bureau (Advertising Manager, Buffalo Evening News), R.K.K., Mr. John Gilgallon, V-PRES, B.B.B.-(Manager, Sears-Roebuck, Buffalo) Robert J. Koch, Commercial Photographer, 193 E. Morris Ave., Buffalo 14, N.Y, 21
    - Verso: Mr. Maurice Connell, TREASURER, Better Business Bureau, Mr. Verden Draper, PRESIDENT-ELECT, B.B.B. (General Partner, Price-Waterhouse, Buffalo), Mr. Edward Butler, PRESIDENT (1967), B.B.B. (President, McDougall-Butler Paint Co.), L.T., Mr. Abner Homburger, CHAIRMAN, Public Relations Committee, B.B.Bureau (Advertising Manager, Buffalo Evening News), R.K.K., Mr. John Gilgallon, V-PRES, B.B.B.-(Manager, Sears-Roebuck, Buffalo) Robert J. Koch, Commercial Photographer, 193 E. Morris Ave., Buffalo 14, N.Y, 21-verso
    - L to R: Mr. Butler, L.T., R.K.K., Mr. Gilgallon Robert J. Koch, Commercial Photographer, 193 E. Morris Ave., Buffalo 14, N.Y., 22
    - Verso: L to R: Mr. Butler, L.T., R.K.K., Mr. Gilgallon Robert J. Koch, Commercial Photographer, 193 E. Morris Ave., Buffalo 14, N.Y., 22-verso
    - June 15, 1965; Lowell Thomas, veteran broadcaster, author and explorer, today joined ceremonies marking the NYSE listings of Capital Cities Broadcasting Corporation, of which he is a founder and director. From the left are: Keith Funston, Exchange President; Lowell Thomas; Frank M. Smith, company chairman and Harold Mackey of McMannus & Mackey, specialists in the stock. Mr. Thomas bought the first 100 shares (ticker symbol CCB) at 37 ½ to open trading. The company, headquartered in New York, operates radio and TV stations in six states, 23
    - Note: From: New York Stock Exchange, 11 Wall Street, New York, New York 10005, Contact: Ralph H. Jones, Hanover 2-4200-Ext. 887, For immediate release, New York, N.Y., June 15, 1965; Lowell Thomas, veteran broadcaster, author and explorer, today joined ceremonies marking the NYSE listings of Capital Cities Broadcasting Corporation, of which he is a founder and director. From the left are: Keith Funston, Exchange President; Lowell Thomas; Frank M. Smith, company chairman and Harold Mackey of McMannus & Mackey, specialists in the stock. Mr. Thomas bought the first 100 shares (ticker symbol CCB) at 37 ½ to open trading. The company, headquartered in New York, operates radio and TV stations in six states, 24
    - [Lowell Thomas at the New York Stock Exchange], 25
    - [Lowell Thomas at the New York Stock Exchange], 26
    - [Lowell Thomas at the New York Stock Exchange] [3 copies], 27
    - [Lowell Thomas at the New York Stock Exchange] [4 copies], 28
    - [Six unidentified men in suits], 29
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man], 30
    - Ray Shafer [Governor of Pennsylvania], Dick S[?] - (Mellon) [Lowell Thomas at left], 31
    - Verso: Ray Shafer [Governor of Pennsylvania], Dick S[?] - (Mellon) [Lowell Thomas at left], 31-verso
  - Subject files: Ralph Carr, Governor of Colorado, circa 1950; 9 (Box 1539)
    - Note: very important to keep, 1
    - L - R: Ralph Carr, Dan Sullivan, Lowell Thomas; taken Denver, Colo [Colorado], 1950? Fred M. Mazzulla, 2
    - Verso: L - R: Ralph Carr, Dan Sullivan, Lowell Thomas; taken Denver, Colo [Colorado], 1950? Fred M. Mazzulla, 2v
    - With Gov [Governor] Ralph Carr, 3
    - Verso: With Gov [Governor] Ralph Carr; photograph by Fred M. Mazzulla, Denver, Colorado, 3v
  - Subject files: Cartoons, circa 1920 - 1974; 10 (Box 1539)
    - L. T. and Warren King, 1974, 1
    - Verso: L. T. and Warren King, 1974, 1-verso
    - Daily Mail, Sandon[?] [2 copies], 2
    - Verso: Daily Mail, Sandon[?], 2-verso
    - Caption: Lowell Thomas cartooned in Londed when he was presenting his own film "With Lawrence in Arabia" at The Royal Opera House for the longest run in history. 1,000,000 people attended, with it was the first film prologue in history [circa 1920], 3
    - Caricature of Lowell Thomas, 4
    - Note: [letter to L.T. from John G. Despeaux] September 27, 1938 My dear Mr. Thomas- A few years agp I sent you a very serious, 5
    - [Illustration from The New Yorker], 6
    - [page from The New Yorker], 7
    - [Cartoon featuring Lowell Thomas], 8
    - Note: The drawing on the bottom represents the consternation of certain members - finding out for the first time, that the "men's comfort rooms" at the Civic Center where moved to a new location 100 yards away, 9
    - [Cartoon featuring Lowell Thomas] [2 copies], 10
    - Wheew! Well, here he is at last. A big 8 pound 10 ounce boy, aho'll cut this teeth, 11
    - Verso: Wheew! Well, here he is at last. A big 8 pound 10 ounce boy, aho'll cut this teeth, 11-verso
    - Note: [with 10.11] Lt. SJ Bradley, 12
    - [cartoon], 13
    - Note: [with 10.13] Dear Lowell, Thought you might like to have attached as a sort of memento. Cordially, [signed] Lynn Mahan, 14
    - [Lowell Thomas] [2 copies], 15
  - Subject files: Cartoons [includes one color photograph], undated; 11 (Box 1539)
    - [RCA Cunningham Radiotron Studio Party poster. "How many can you identify? Ask for key sheet Radio Tubes Tested Free"], 1
    - [Drawing of Lowell Thomas holding a microphone-1980(?)], 2
    - [Drawing of Lowell Thomas by John. G. Despeaux], 3
    - Verso: To- Lowell Thomas, With Best Wishes, John G. Despeaux, 3-verso
    - [Cartoon of Lowell Thomas by Lowell Thomas titled "Fan Mail"], 4
    - Caption: To Lowell Thomas Newscaster, Explorer, World-Traveller & Bank-Brush Impressario from Fred Anderson, 5
    - Caption: So long until, 6
    - Caption: I missed the reptile and ran away as fast as I could!, 7
    - Caption: I missed the reptile and ran away as fast as I could!, 8
    - [Sketch of Lowell Thomas sitting on the globe, "Global Thomas"], 9
    - Caption: "Poor L.T.! But it's how he'd have wanted to go!", 10
  - Subject files: Cartoons (High Adventure with Lowell Thomas television series), 1959; 12 (Box 1539)
    - Note: "High Adventure" vagabonds sail to Arabia on last stop of season's television trail; Aboard the good ship "Odyssey" (Odyssey Productions), Lowell Thomas and his son, Lowell, Jr. sail into the Persian Gulf for the last seasonal installment of "High Adventure With Lowell Thomas" Friday, March 27 (CBS Television Network), 8:00-9:00 PM, EST). Earlier this television season, before navigating their rugged way into the upcoming "Arabian Nights" adventure, the international vagabonds visited Alaska, the Belgian Congo and the Pacific's Danger Island; Subject: Lowell Thomas, Sr. and Jr.; Program: "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas"; On Air: Friday, March 27, 8:00-9:00 PM, EST; Sponsor: General Motors Corp; "Full" 2/27/1959, 1
    - Cartoon featuring Lowell Thomas, Lowell Thomas, Jr. [15 copies], 2
  - Subject files: Cartoons (Paul Webb) [includes one color photograph], circa 1930s, 1976; 13 (Box 1539)
    - [circa 1930s][Cartoon mentioning Lowell Thomas. Letter: "Dear Lowell-The boys just couldn't refrain from including their own greeting in return for the many hamburgers enjoyed during the summer-Paul Webh" (?)], 1
    - Caption: Happy 84th - Loel - they don't make em like u an me no more. Granpap [1976], 2
  - Subject files: Carol Channing and Charles Lowe [holiday greeting], 1968; 14 (Box 1539)
    - Caption: Carol Channing and Charles Lowe 1968, 1
  - Subject files: Harry Chase, circa 1918; 15 (Box 1539)
    - Harry A. Chase, Globe photographer who accompanied Mr. Thomas on most of his travels wearing the helmet of Chancellor Von Bethmann-Hollweg. This is the helmet of a Prussian General, 1
    - Verso: Harry A. Chase, Globe photographer who accompanied Mr. Thomas on most of his travels wearing the helmet of Chancellor Von Bethmann-Hollweg. This is the helmet of a Prussian General, 1-verso
    - [Harry Chase wearing Arab robe and headdress] [2 copies], 2
  - Subject files: Winston Churchill [novelist], circa 1917; 16 (Box 1539)
    - Winston Churchill, 1
    - Verso: Winston Churchill, 1-verso
  - Subject files: Cinerama, 1950s; 17 (Box 1539)
    - Frank Smith, Dick Pistell on right, 1
    - Verso: Frank Smith, Dick Pistell on right, 1-verso
    - Banshees Luncheon on Nov. 8, 1951; Count von Luckner [seated at right of Lowell Thomas], L. T., Fred Waller, Mike Todd, [Hazard] "Buzz" Reeves, Frank Smith. On left Dudley Roberts, then three I don't recall, 2
    - Verso: Banshees Luncheon on Nov. 8, 1951; Count von Luckner [seated at right of Lowell Thomas], L. T., Fred Waller, Mike Todd, [Hazard] "Buzz" Reeves, Frank Smith. On left Dudley Roberts, then three I don't recall, 2-verso
    - Left to right: Dudley Robert, ?, Count Von Luckner, L.T., Fred Waller, Mike Todd, Boss Reeves, Frank Smith [3 copies], 3
    - Verso: Left to right: Dudley Robert, ?, Count Von Luckner, L.T., Fred Waller, Mike Todd, Boss Reeves, Frank Smith, 3-verso
    - L.T. and Gen. Merian Cooper, famous film producer, co-producer or Cinerama with L.T. [5 copies], 4
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas with Marion [sic] [Merian] Cooper founder of Cinerama. Involved with original King Kong; The Alfred Sloan Dinner at Waldorf, 4-verso
    - Note: L.T. and Gen. Merian Cooper, famous film producer, co-producer or Cinerama with L.T., 5
    - [Merian Cooper publicity photograph], 6
    - L. T. and Sam Rosen of Stanley-Warner (personal file), 7
    - Verso: L. T. and Sam Rosen of Stanley-Warner (personal file), 7-verso
    - [Man loading film], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas and two men looking at film (?)], 9
    - [Hazard Reeves?], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas giving a speech at Hotel Statler at Cimerama] [2 copies], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas delivering a speech at Cimerama], 12
  - Subject files: Cinerama, 1950s; 18 (Box 1539)
    - Star put on sidewalk in front of Cinerama Theater in Hollywood (sometime after 1952), 1
    - Note: Star put on sidewalk in front of Cinerama Theater in Hollywood (sometime after 1952), 2
    - Edward Pryor and Richard Castle Cinerama technicians inspect a section of the Cinerama sound track recording of translated narrative into 19 foreign languages, 3
    - Verso: Edward Pryor and Richard Castle Cinerama technicians inspect a section of the Cinerama sound track recording of translated narrative into 19 foreign languages, 3-verso
    - With Joan Crawford at opening of "The Seven Wonders of the World"; Norm:-suggest cut off man on right, 4
    - Verso: With Joan Crawford at opening of "The Seven Wonders of the World"; Norm:-suggest cut off man on right, 4-verso
    - Tom Conroy, Vice President Cinerama, surveys sound testing equipment prior to installation in the sound recording section of the new Cinerama technical laboratory, 5
    - Verso: Tom Conroy, Vice President Cinerama, surveys sound testing equipment prior to installation in the sound recording section of the new Cinerama technical laboratory, 5-verso
    - Caption: A Hycon P-38, modified for high altitude (36,000 to 40,000 feet above sea level) photographic work Verso: Mr. Perley's P-38, 6
    - Edison's first motion pix lab. [picture laboratory]; Note: Does this go with Cinerama - Yes, 7
    - Verso: Edison's first motion pix lab. [picture laboratory], 7-verso
    - Note: Does this go with Cinerama - Yes; [with 18.6], 8
    - The Forum Cinerama laboratory screen to be used for editing of new productions occupies the entire proscenium of the once popular show place and will be the largest screen ever installed in the history of the motions picture industry, 9
    - Verso: The Forum Cinerama laboratory screen to be used for editing of new productions occupies the entire proscenium of the once popular show place and will be the largest screen ever installed in the history of the motions picture industry, 9-verso
    - [Cinerama Studio] [2 copies], 10
    - T. L. Perkins, 11
    - Verso: T. L. Perkins, 11-verso
    - [Unidentified man with a pipe], 12
    - Camel chewing on caravan route along Indus River; photo by Chris Young, 13
    - Verso: Camel chewing on caravan route along Indus River; photo by Chris Young, 13-verso
    - NEW YORK BUREAU; PUTTING AN ODYSSEY ON FILM, CAIRO: - Globe-trotter Lowell Thomas, producing a film called "Seven Wonders of the World," stands before two ancient marvels in Egypt - the Great Pyramid of Cheops (background) and the Sphinx. The noted commentator and adventurer recently completed a globe-circling trip to 32 countries working on the film, the third "Cinerama" production. The modern odyssey covered 100,000 miles and the Cinerama crew worked with two airplanes and five directors; CREDTI (UNITED PRESS PHOTO) 11/18/55, 14
    - Note: NEW YORK BUREAU; PUTTING AN ODYSSEY ON FILM, CAIRO: - Globe-trotter Lowell Thomas, producing a film called "Seven Wonders of the World," stands before two ancient marvels in Egypt - the Great Pyramid of Cheops (background) and the Sphinx. The noted commentator and adventurer recently completed a globe-circling trip to 32 countries working on the film, the third "Cinerama" production. The modern odyssey covered 100,000 miles and the Cinerama crew worked with two airplanes and five directors; CREDTI (UNITED PRESS PHOTO) 11/18/55, 15
    - [Lowell Thomas standing in the middle of many microphones], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas and two other blowing out a candle], 17
  - Subject files: Cinerama (Austria), 1950s; 19 (Box 1539)
    - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession on the Trausse in Upper Austria, 1
    - Verso: Corpus Christi Day: Church procession on the Trausse in Upper Austria, 1-verso
    - Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession on the Hallstatt Lake in Upper Austria, 2
    - Verso: Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession on the Hallstatt Lake in Upper Austria, 2-verso
    - Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession at Solden in the Otz Valley (Tyrol), 3
    - Verso: Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession at Solden in the Otz Valley (Tyrol), 3-verso
    - Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession at Solden in the Otz Valley (Tyrol), 4
    - Verso: Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession at Solden in the Otz Valley (Tyrol), 4-verso
    - Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession at Solden in the Otz Valley (Tyrol), 5
    - Verso: Austria - Corpus Christi Day: Church procession at Solden in the Otz Valley (Tyrol), 5-verso
    - Austria - Schemenlaufen (masked dance) at Imst in the Tyrol, 6
    - Verso: Austria - Schemenlaufen (masked dance) at Imst in the Tyrol, 6-verso
    - Austria - Schemenlaufen (masked dance) at Imst in the Tyrol, 7
    - Verso: Austria - Schemenlaufen (masked dance) at Imst in the Tyrol, 7-verso
    - Austria - Schellerlaufen (masked dance) at Nassereith in the Tyrol, 8
    - Verso: Austria - Schellerlaufen (masked dance) at Nassereith in the Tyrol, 8-verso
    - Austria - Schleicherlaufen (masked dance) at Telfs in the Tyrol, 9
    - Verso: Austria - Schleicherlaufen (masked dance) at Telfs in the Tyrol, 9-verso
    - Austria - Kufenstechen in Carinthia - a tradition observed at Whitsuntide, 10
    - Verso: Austria - Kufenstechen in Carinthia - a tradition observed at Whitsuntide, 10-verso
    - Austria - Kufenstechen in Gail Valley in Carinthia - a tradition observed at Whitsuntide, 11
    - Verso: Austria - Kufenstechen in Gail Valley in Carinthia - a tradition observed at Whitsuntide, 11-verso
  Box 1540
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Cinerama (Greece), 1950s; 1 (Box 1540)
    - Epidaurus theatre, 1
    - Verso: Epidaurus theatre, 1-verso
    - Greece, national dance, 2
    - Verso: Greece, national dance, 2-verso
    - Greece [?], ancient theater "[?] Atticus", Aeschylus tragedy "Orestia", 3
    - Verso: Greece [?], ancient theater "[?] Atticus", Aeschylus tragedy "Orestia", 3-verso
    - Greece - Euripides' "Hippolytus" from the "Tradedy [sic] [Tragedy] Festival held at the Ancient Theatre of Epidaurus (ii July and 8 Aug. 1954), 4
    - Verso: Greece - Euripides' "Hippolytus" from the "Tradedy [sic] [Tragedy] Festival held at the Ancient Theatre of Epidaurus (ii July and 8 Aug. 1954), 4-verso
    - Greece - Euripides' "Hippolytus" from the "Tradedy [sic] [Tragedy] Festival held at the Ancient Theatre of Epidaurus (ii July and 8 Aug. 1954), 5
    - Verso: Greece - Euripides' "Hippolytus" from the "Tradedy [sic] [Tragedy] Festival held at the Ancient Theatre of Epidaurus (ii July and 8 Aug. 1954), 5-verso
    - Epidaurus, 6
    - Verso: Epidaurus, 6-verso
    - Greece - local costume of a Greek island, 7
    - Verso: Greece - local costume of a Greek island, 7-verso
    - Greece - fishermen, 8
    - Verso: Greece - fishermen, 8-verso
    - Greece - dance of Poutos[?] in Kessariani[?]; Greek folk dancing, 9
    - Verso: Greece - dance of Poutos[?] in Kessariani[?]; Greek folk dancing, 9-verso
    - Greece - Delphi; countryside on edge of ancient Delphi theatre, 10
    - Verso: Greece - Delphi; countryside on edge of ancient Delphi theatre, 10-verso
    - Greece, 11
    - Verso: Greece, 11-verso
    - Lowell, The Euzones do a special dance too [?] which we could film [?] our episode, Maynard [Miller?], 12
    - Verso: Lowell, The Euzones do a special dance too [?] which we could film [?] our episode, Maynard [Miller?], 12-verso
    - Caption: Euzone du Palais Royale; Written caption: Have also obtained permission to film these gentlemen whenever we want them - perhaps at Olympia [from M3, Maynard Miller?], 13
    - Verso: [letter written to Lowell Thomas], 13-verso
    - [Buildings on top of a high rock in Greece], 14
    - [Theater in Greece], 15
    - [Ancient theatre in Greece], 16
  - Subject files: Cinerama (Indus River, photography by Otto Lang), 1956; 2 (Box 1540)
    - Preparations prior to departure from Gilgit ("Bus" hatch, Chris Young, Don hatch and native boy holding umbrella); photo: Otto Lang, 1
    - Verso: Preparations prior to departure from Gilgit ("Bus" hatch, Chris Young, Don hatch and native boy holding umbrella); photo: Otto Lang, 1-verso
    - Preparing boat, prior to departure from Gilgit (native boy holding umbrella, Chris Young, "Bus" Hatch and Don Hatch); photo: Otto Lang, 2
    - Verso: Preparing boat, prior to departure from Gilgit (native boy holding umbrella, Chris Young, "Bus" Hatch and Don Hatch); photo: Otto Lang, 2-verso
    - rigging camera on day of accident, July 20, 1956. Mike Zingale, Jack Priestly, Joe Speizio; photo: Otto Lang, 3
    - Verso: rigging camera on day of accident, July 20, 1956. Mike Zingale, Jack Priestly, Joe Speizio; photo: Otto Lang, 3-verso
    - Exact spot of accident, when raft turned over (arrow pointing); photo: Otto Lang, 4
    - Verso: Exact spot of accident, when raft turned over (arrow pointing); photo: Otto Lang, 4-verso
    - A typical Indus River rapid, which looks diminutive without object of scale of comparison; photo: Otto Lang, 5
    - Verso: A typical Indus River rapid, which looks diminutive without object of scale of comparison; photo: Otto Lang, 5-verso
    - Prior to departure of Indus gorges above Skardu; "Bus" Hatch, Don Hatch, Otto Lang, 6
    - Verso: Prior to departure of Indus gorges above Skardu; "Bus" Hatch, Don Hatch, Otto Lang, 6-verso
  - Subject files: Cinerama (Indus River, photography by Chris Young), 1956; 3 (Box 1540)
    - Nauga Parbat 26,000 ft high, 1
    - Verso: Nauga Parbat 26,000 ft high, 1-verso
    - Camera crew waiting for sun to come out, 2
    - Verso: Camera crew waiting for sun to come out, 2-verso
    - Camera crew waiting for sun to come out, 3
    - Verso: Camera crew waiting for sun to come out, 3-verso
    - getting equipment down to camera location, 4
    - Verso: getting equipment down to camera location, 4-verso
    - getting equipment down with ropes, 5
    - Verso: getting equipment down with ropes, 5-verso
    - Camel caravan on caravan route along Indus, 6
    - Verso: Camel caravan on caravan route along Indus, 6-verso
    - Caravan route along Indus river, 7
    - Verso: Caravan route along Indus river, 7-verso
    - Cinerama camera, left, shooting Don Hatch, 8
    - Verso: Cinerama camera, left, shooting Don Hatch, 8-verso
    - Don Hatch in little boat, 9
    - Verso: Don Hatch in little boat, 9-verso
    - Don Hatch in small boat, 10
    - Verso: Don Hatch in small boat, 10-verso
    - Don Hatch in small boat on Indus, 11
    - Verso: Don Hatch in small boat on Indus, 11-verso
    - Otto Lang painting name, 12
    - Verso: Otto Lang painting name, 12-verso
    - Little boat (small dot) big boat behind, 13
    - Verso: Little boat (small dot) big boat behind, 13-verso
    - Big boat with little boat tied to it, 14
    - Verso: Big boat with little boat tied to it, 14-verso
    - Indus River lower left, 15
    - Verso: Indus River lower left, 15-verso
    - Little boat (small dot) big boat behind, 16
    - Verso: Little boat (small dot) big boat behind, 16-verso
    - Rapids on Indus River, 17
    - Verso: Rapids on Indus River, 17-verso
    - Rapids on Indus River, 18
    - Verso: Rapids on Indus River, 18-verso
  - Subject files: Cinerama (Japan) [includes one color photograph], 1957; 4 (Box 1540)
    - Emperor of Japan, 1
    - Verso: Emperor of Japan, 1-verso
    - Empress attends to Cinerama Prod. No. 3 "Seven Wonders" at the Imperial Theatre, Tokyo, 1957; right to left: Princess Chichibu, Empress Nagako, 2
    - Verso: Empress attends to Cinerama Prod. No. 3 "Seven Wonders" at the Imperial Theatre, Tokyo, 1957; right to left: Princess Chichibu, Empress Nagako, 2-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas], 3
    - in Kashmir, 4
    - Verso: in Kashmir, 4-verso
  - Subject files: Cinerama (Nepalese delegation), 1956; 5 (Box 1540)
    - Left to right, of the Nepalese group: Mr. H. M. Singh, His Highness Probaker Shumshere, Cinerama director Otto Lang, his Royal Highness Prince Himalaya, your charming hostess who conducted part to the roof, Her Royal Highness Princess Himalaya; In front of Princess: Master Shaha, son of Ambassador Shri Rishikes Shaha, Madam Shaha, the boy's mother, Mr. Lhendup Dorji, 1
    - Note: Left to right, of the Nepalese group: Mr. H. M. Singh, His Highness Probaker Shumshere, Cinerama director Otto Lang, his Royal Highness Prince Himalaya, your charming hostess who conducted part to the roof, Her Royal Highness Princess Himalaya; In front of Princess: Master Shaha, son of Ambassador Shri Rishikes Shaha, Madam Shaha, the boy's mother, Mr. Lhendup Dorji, 2
  - Subject files: Cinerama (James Parker), circa 1956; 6 (Box 1540)
    - "Search for Paradise", Jim Parker, 1
    - Note: "Search for Paradise", Jim Parker, 2
    - Copyright Otto Lang. 'Jimmy' - Search for Paradise maybe he found it!!!, 3
    - Verso: Copyright Otto Lang. 'Jimmy' - Search for Paradise maybe he found it!!!, 3-verso
  - Subject files: Cinerama premiere (Detroit, Michigan), 1953 February - March; 7 (Box 1540)
    - DETROIT PREMIERE - Crack precision drill squadron from University of Detroit Air Reserves perform front of Music hall at Midwest premiere, Tuesday, Fe. 11 (Note: first time that snowflakes have ever taken this form in my newspaper career, usually streaks are the effect); From: Bill Green, Cinerama, 1